younesnejahi

about

Bellevue, WA (313) 236-1072 I am a motivated, enthusiastic, detailed-oriented, and committed engineer. I have 5 years experience in developing and maintaining open source project (GOMC), which I learned how to communicate, document, design, program, and automatically test.

younesnejahi@gmail.com younesn.github.io linkedin.com/in/nejahi

languages

English Farsi

programming

♥ C/C++, Python CUDA, MPI, OpenMP Bash, PHP, JavaScript Matlab, Swift, OpenCL

web and markups

HTML, HTML5, AJAX MySQL, CSS, CSS3 LATEX, Markdown

tools

NVIDIA NSight Systems/Compute, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Jupyter, SVN, Grace

miscellaneous

strong verbal and written communcation skills, excellent troubleshooting and debugging skills, exceptional problem solving skills, great team skills

2014-Now Graduate Research Assistant

Wayne State University

Collaborated with 9 more students to develop the fastest Monte Carlo simulation engine (GOMC) equipped with OpenMP and CUDA to fully utilize multi-core and heterogeneous architectures. My contributions:

- Profiled, ported the bottleneck of GOMC to GPU which improved the performance by up to 100x.
- Additional 16x speed-up gained on 2020 SDSC/NVIDIA GPU hackathon.
- Developed automated testing suite and reduced testing time from 1 week
- Moved project from SVN to GitHub, added CircleCl, documentation repository, and slack channel for more clear communication.

Web Developer

https://shgsilica.eng.wayne.edu/ & http://jetscape.org/

education

experience

2014-2020	Ph.D. Doctor of Philosophy Majoring in Computer Science	Wayne State University
2013-2014	M.Sc. Master of Science Majoring in Computer Science	Wayne State University
2007–2012	B.Sc. Bachelor of Science Majoring in Computer Science	Isfahan University of Technology

projects

GOMC	GPU-Optimized	Monte Carlo
adivid	ur o-obuillizeu	With the Carry

Open-source software for simulating molecular systems using the Metropolis

Monte Carlo algorithm.

PSO-GOF Particle Swarm Optimization - Gibbs Optimization of force field

Fully automated optimization tool written in Python/MPI scaled to hundred of

nodes.

Stencil-GPU Stencil computation implemented on GPU utilizing Warp Shuffle technology

Improved stencil computation by factor of 1.8X compared to previous fastest

implementation.

awards and honors

Mar 2018 **Outstanding Graduate Research Award** Detroit, MI

2009 & 2010 Honorable Mention at Regional Contest of ACM-ICPC, West Asia Site Tehran, Iran